tinuiti.com 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy | Tinuiti

## Your privacy is critically important to us.

### At Tinuiti we have a few fundamental principles:

**We don’t ask** you for personal information unless we truly need it and the only reasons would be to contact us to hear about our services, join our newsletter, download or sign up to receive content, offer our services, or join our team (we can’t stand services that ask you for things like your gender or income level for no apparent reason).

**We don’t share** your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our services, or protect our rights.

**We don’t store** personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services or as specified on our form.

EFFECTIVE MAY 16, 2019

BELOW IS OUR PRIVACY POLICY WHICH INCORPORATES THESE GOALS:

_Click on one of the hyperlinks to take you directly to that section of the notice._  
[Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information – Sharing and Disclosure](https://elitesem.com/privacy-policy/#protectionofcertainpersonally)  

### Personal Data Collected

Information collected on the website

Tinuiti Inc. (“Tinuiti”) operates tinuiti.com and CPC Strategy.com. It is Tinuiti’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

Tinuiti is a data controller for data collected on this website.

While using our website, we ask you to provide us with certain personal data that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Data”). Personal Data includes, but is not limited to:

  * Email address
  * First name and last name
  * Phone number
  * Address, State, Province, ZIP/Postal code, City
  * Job title, profession
  * Company name and URL

**Information Received from Clients**

Tinuiti receives data from its clients and processes this data per contract in place with our clients. Tinuiti does not have a direct relationship with these individuals.

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, Tinuiti collects information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Tinuiti’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Tinuiti’s visitors use its website.

Tinuiti also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on blogs if available. Tinuiti only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below.

**Aggregated Statistics**

Tinuiti collects statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Tinuiti monitors the most popular blog posts or pages on the site. Tinuiti may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Tinuiti does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Use of your information – Grounds for Using Your Personal Data

As mentioned, the information that Tinuiti collects and stores relating to you is used to communicate to you and to provide our services to you. In addition, Tinuiti relies on the following lawful grounds to collect and process any personal data you may have provided:

  * **Legitimate Business Interests:** To notify you about any changes or improvements to Tinuiti services that may affect our service. If you are an existing customer, Tinuiti
  * **Performance of Contract:** To meet Tinuiti’s contractual commitments to our clients and in performance of contractual obligations to our clients.
  * **User Consent:** If you are a user of a Tinuiti website and have supplied your email address and provided consent, Tinuiti may occasionally send you email to tell you about industry news and information, solicit your feedback, or keep you up to date with what’s going on with Tinuiti and our services. We primarily use our email newsletter or email you updates on our blog to communicate this type of information.

Tinuiti takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

Tinuiti may use your data so that you can be provided with information about related goods and services which we believe may be of interest to you. Tinuiti may contact you about these goods and services by any of the methods that you consented to at the time your information was collected.

If you are a new customer, Tinuiti will only contact you when you have provided consent and only by those means you provided consent for.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information – Sharing and Disclosure

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Tinuiti uses cookies to help Tinuiti identify and track visitors, their usage of Tinuiti website, and their website access preferences. Tinuiti visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Tinuiti’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Tinuiti’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

Tinuiti does not share your personal information with others except as indicated within this policy or when we inform you and give you an opportunity to opt out of having your personal information shared.

  * **Analytics.** Specifically for analytics providers, we use Google Analytics and Marketo. Google Analytics, which is a web analytics service offered by Google, and Marketo, a 3rd party inbound marketing and sales software, track and report website traffic. Both services uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service.Google Analytics shares this data with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity. For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/ Google also recommends installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on – https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout – for your web browser. Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on provides visitors with the ability to prevent their data from being collected and used by Google Analytics.You can also request access, correction, updates or deletion of your personal information we collect via Marketo. If we have collected and process your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us or clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located at the bottom of our email communication. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent. To exercise these rights, please contact us at [marketing@tinuiti.com](mailto:marketing@elitesem.com). For more information on the privacy practices of Marketo, please visit their Privacy Policy: [https://www.marketo.com/company/trust/security/](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy?__hstc=161864675.9484c955a6bfe17a84d18d6aeff5724a.1557160592345.1557160592345.1557160592345.1&__hssc=161864675.2.1557160592346&__hsfp=3556845864)
  * **Advertising.** We may use third-party Service Providers to show advertisements, which may include targeted advertisements on a third party site after you have visited our website. We and the third party service providers use cookies to inform, optimize, measure performance serve ads based on your previous visits to our site. Any tracking that a third party performs is subject to their own privacy notice. Our third party service providers may provide us information that tells us how are marketing ads, often placed on third party sites, performed and who clicked on them. This information does not identify any specific individual and is generally non-identifying. If we were to associate it with you we would treat it as personal data.

Please note at this time, we do not recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, which may include “do not track” instructions.

We work with Google AdSense & DoubleClick Cookie Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our Service or other websites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick Cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the Google Ads Settings web page: http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/

Google AdWords/Analytics: Google AdWords remarketing service is provided by Google Inc.  
You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize the Google Display Network ads by visiting the Google Ads Settings page: http://www.google.com/settings/ads

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page at http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/

Facebook: You can learn more about interest-based advertising from Facebook by visiting this page: https://www.facebook.com/help/164968693837950

To opt-out from Facebook’s interest-based ads follow these instructions from Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217  
To see more about Facebook’s participation in the Digital Advertising Alliance please visit the Choices section of this notice.

For more information on the privacy practices of Facebook, please visit Facebook’s Data Policy: https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation

We may participate in Facebook.com’s Custom Audience or LinkedIn’s Audience program which enables us to display personalized ads to persons on our email list when they visit Facebook or LinkedIn respectively. We provide Personal Information such as your email address and phone number to the social media provider to enable it to determine if you are a registered account holder. You may opt-out of participation in this program by contacting us as noted below. You may also opt out of receiving these ads from the social media network directly.

### Third Party service providers, employees, agents or contractors

Tinuiti discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Tinuiti’s behalf or to provide services available at Tinuiti’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Tinuiti’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Tinuiti will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone with advance notice. We do share information as described above with our website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential.

### Third-party Disclosure for Joint Marketing Events & Digital Assets

For users in the United States, we sometimes participate in joint marketing events with third parties. On the registration page, it is clear who the other joint marketing party is. If you opt-into a joint marketing event or digital asset in the United States, we may provide your registration information to these third parties & partners for use in marketing and in designing or providing their own services, to send you information about its products and to notify you if you win a contest. You may opt out of us providing such information by opting out of our email newsletter and/or not registering for joint marketing events. You should contact the other third party directly who may already be sending you messages in order to request that these communications stop, and to review their privacy policies.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

### To Comply with legal process or to protect Tinuiti

Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Tinuiti discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Tinuiti believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Tinuiti, third parties or the public at large.

### Business Transfers

If Tinuiti, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Tinuiti goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Tinuiti may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

### Storing your personal data/Transfer of Data

Tinuiti operates its site in the United States. If you are located in another jurisdiction, please know that your information will be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States. By using this site and providing Tinuiti with information, you consent to this transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States. It is important to note that the privacy laws in the United States may not be as comprehensive as those in other countries such as the European Union. Tinuiti service providers use appropriate safeguards to transfer your personal data to the United States.

  * Tinuiti may transfer data that we collect from you to locations outside of headquarters for processing and storing. In addition, it may be processed by staff operating outside the office area who work for us or for one of our suppliers. For example, such staff may be engaged in the processing and concluding of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. Tinuiti will take all reasonable steps to make sure that your data is treated securely and in agreement with this privacy policy.
  * Data that is provided to Tinuiti is stored on our secure servers. Details relating to any transactions entered into via the Tinuiti site will be encrypted to ensure its safety.
  * The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure and therefore Tinuiti cannot guarantee the security of data sent to Tinuiti electronically and the transmission of such data is entirely at your own risk. Where Tinuiti has given you (or where you have chosen) a password so that you can access certain areas of the Tinuiti site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.

### Third party links

Tinuiti may have links on the Tinuiti site to other sites that Tinuiti does not operate. If you click on a third-party link, you will be taken directly to that site which is governed by its own privacy notice. Tinuiti strongly encourages you to read that privacy notice. Tinuiti does not control that site and assume no responsibility for the content, policies or its practices.

### Choices and Individual Rights

Tinuiti aims to take reasonable steps, so you can correct, amend, delete or limit the use of your Personal Data. If you are a customer of one of our clients that works with Tinuiti and would no longer like to be contacted by them, please send your request to the client that you interact with directly. If our client requests Tinuiti to remove or amend that data, we will respond to that request within 30 days.

Tinuiti outlines your choices below:

  * Email. As described above, if you do not wish to receive promotional emails from Tinuiti or for us to share your information with a joint partner in co-branded marketing events, you may opt out at any time. If you opt out of a promotional email, Tinuiti may still send you transactional and administrative emails about this privacy notice or about the products or services you have purchased.
  * **Cookies.** Your browser’s help function should contain instructions on how to set your computer to accept all cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued, or to not receive cookies at any time.
  * **Advertising.** You can opt out of online targeted advertising by opting out within the advertisement itself or by visiting Digital Advertising Alliance, http://www.aboutads.info/, the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada in Canada http://youradchoices.ca/ or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance in Europe http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/. You can also opt out of the Digital Advertising Alliance using your mobile device settings.
  * **Your rights under certain circumstances.** To initiate any of these actions please contact us at marketing@tinuiti.com. 
    * To access and receive a copy of the Personal Data we hold about you.
    * To rectify any Personal Data held about you that is inaccurate
    * To request the deletion of Personal Data held about you
    * You have the right to data portability for the information you have provided to us. You can request to obtain a copy of this information in a commonly used electronic format so that you can manage and move it. We will need to verify your identity before being able to respond to such requests.
    * Please note that in some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
  * **Right to Lodge a Complaint.** For European Union residents, if you feel that Tinuiti’s processing of your personal data infringes on data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state where you habitually reside, your place of work or the location of the alleged infringement. If you are located outside of the European Union, you may have rights under privacy laws in the jurisdiction where you live.

### Security

Tinuiti uses reasonable administrative, logical, physical and managerial measures to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft and unauthorized access, use and modification. Unfortunately, no measures can be guaranteed to provide 100% security. Accordingly, Tinuiti cannot guarantee the security of your information.

### Sensitive Data

Tinuiti requests that you do not send us any sensitive data such as social security or national identification numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health data, biometrics or genetic, criminal background or trade union membership information. If you do send Tinuiti this information, then you are consenting to its processing in accordance with this privacy notice. To avoid processing of sensitive data, do not submit it.

### Our policy on children’s information

The Tinuiti site is not directed to children under 16. If you learn that your minor child has provided Tinuiti with personal information without your consent, please contact Tinuiti.

### Contact Us

Tinuiti welcomes any queries, comments or requests you may have regarding this policy please do not hesitate to contact us at marketing@tinuiti.com.

Tinuiti is the Data Controller for information collected on this website and can be reached at:

Tinuiti  
Attn: Marketing Dept  
142 W 36th St, Fl 11  
New York, NY 10018

Information that is provided to Tinuiti from its clients is controlled by them.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Tinuiti may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Tinuiti’s sole discretion.
